# DEE XIAO「萧笛」

+86 (186) 0164-0024 mopjtv@gmail.com deexiao.com

#### 个人简介

MS graduate student from <u>Arizona State University</u> who can bring a diverse skill set and creative drive to software application development. Proficient in writing code in various languages, and feature development and implementation. Specialized in thinking outside the box to find unique solutions to difficult engineering problems.

#### 教育经历

「美国 本科」 Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Arizona State University - USA GPA: 3.6 / 4.0 Jan 2013 - May 2017 「美国 硕士」 Master of Science, Computer Science Arizona State University - USA GPA: 3.5 / 4.0 Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

## 专业技能

- Mobile Development (iOS & Android): Obj-C/Swift, Java/Kotlin
- Other Programming Languages: C++, Python
- Software Development Methodologies: Agile, Scrum
- Web Development: ASP.NET, Vue 2-3, Webpack, TS, SCSS

Aug 2016 - May 2017

- Version Control: 7+ years of intensive Git use
- Automated Testing: JUnit, JMeter, UnixBench

# 工作经验

Product Manager Jan 2020 - Now

#### 壹龙智能科技 (无锡) 有限公司

• Implemented the bid testing to compare the different companies quoted price.

Software Engineer Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

#### 华为技术(上海)有限公司

- Problem Location and Optimization: Analyze and locate the functional problems of MML module.
- Code Cleanup: Responsible for the static cleaning of C++ code in the release work to ensure the code quality of the release.

Web Developer Intern Aug 2018 – Oct 2018

#### Helix House (美国) Digital Advertising Agency

• Reconstructed Website platform to be more responsive, optimized website load, setup up testing instance, reconfigured site for SEO, and enabled Hubspot/ Google Analytics for tracking.

#### Teaching Assistant of Data Structures

# 亚利桑那州立大学(美国)Ira A. Fulton Schools of Engineering

• Assisted Dr. Mutsumi Nakamura with exploratory and collaborative learning activities, met with professor on a regular basis to prepare for exam review sessions and lecture activities.

Software Engineer Intern May 2016 – Aug 2016

#### 飞利浦(中国)投资有限公司 - HSDP (HealthSuite Digital Platform)

- Designed Philips HSDP strategy Deploy, develop and support a cloud platform to connect health and medical devices.
- Implemented the stress testing to compare the virtual machine performance of two public laaS providers (AWS and HUAWEI Cloud).

# 个人开发

SeatsFinder • Published on Apple Store Skills used: iOS (Swift) + ASP.NET + Web API + MVC + SQL Server (MS) + Cloud Deploy (Azure)

- Cross platform: iOS App [Link] + Windows / PC [Link] + Web App [Link] + Python Script [Link]
- Help students get into classes by monitoring opening seats. Students will get alerted whenever the server detects an opening.
- Follow the MVC design pattern, hosted on Azure & GCP and use ASP.NET to do all back-ends including Restful API Calling/Creation.
- DBMS using MS SQL Server and iOS CoreData; iOS In-App-Purchase Membership option to accelerate the server speed.
- SeatsFinder has achieved thousands of users from ASU and hundreds of new users per semester. More info

StockTakes • Published on Apple Store Skills used: iOS (Swift) + ASP.NET + Web API + MVC + Cloud Deploy (Azure)

• Inventory Counter App For PwC employers, hosted on Azure & GCP and use ASP.NET to do all back-ends

# Vue 3 自建造轮子 Skills used: Vue 3 Composition API + Vite + TypeScript + Vue Router + SCSS

- Vue 3.0 based component library for developers, designers and product managers. (Switch, Button, Dialog, Tabs ...)
- Web / Mobile App [Link]

### Vue 2 记账 APP Skills used: Vue 2 + TypeScript + Vue Router + Vuex

- Application for a quick tracking of your expenses and income as well as a control over your personal financial situation.
- Web / Mobile App [Link]